As you manage your project you're going to be creating a lot of data information and reports when you
close out a project.
All of that data all that information even those reports should go into Project archives.
But this doesn't mean that we just stick it in the closet forget about it.
That's information that we can use on future projects.
So that becomes part of organizational process assets will a new process that we'll see in the Pinback
guide 6 addition is knowledge management.
So this sets us up for this idea of knowledge repositories that how do we take that data that information
from our past projects and how can we quickly access that and be able to apply it and use it in our
current project.
So we're talking about cataloguing.
So how do you catalog it electronically.
How do you archive it.
Is it retrievable.
So we have to go dig through you know a closet somewhere.
Hopefully not.
But it's electronic that you can search it and retrieve it.
Organizational process assets these are part of your knowledge repositories of historical information.
So that allows me then to pull from that and apply it to my current project.
We always archive at closure so it's never an option to not archive.
We always archive a closure because that's part of the business value.
That's part of the things that we're creating as part of the project Project deliverables are not always
things that the customer gets.
It could also be things that we get and that we retain as the organization.
So knowledge gain tools equipment.
In this case it's knowledge.
So how do we retrieve that knowledge.
So examples of organizational knowledge repositories obviously project files from past projects.
Lessons learned so lessons learned documentation will see that through out the Pinback that we're updating
lessons learned.
Issue in Defect databases.
So as issues are identified and resolve how did you resolve it.
What defects exist and how did you resolve it.
Or when we resolve it.
So that can help us in our current project and also in future projects and we have the same type of
issue configuration management databases remember configuration management it's all about the features
and functions of the product and we'll see that again in chapter 5 of the Pinback and financial databases.
What was the estimate.
What was the estimated cost and what was the actual cost.
So that could help us better estimate in future projects and the current projects could help us do some
forecasting or trending based on cost.
So this is all part of organizational knowledge repositories and we'll see that again later in the course
when we talk about knowledge management.
All right.
Good job.